<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LEARNING WITH SCKINTA</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on LEARNING WITH SCKINTA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>From R to Python: Data Wrangling (part1)</title>
      <link>/post/2019-10-22_data_wrangling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-10-22_data_wrangling/</guid>
      <description>Data wrangling usually stands as the first step for any data scientist. I started to learn data science by reading the book “R for Data Science”. The book is mainly an intro to the tidyverse, which is a collection of R packages designed for data science. It has its own grammar/syntax that can help users efficiently deal with data wrangling, visualization, string/date management, etc. As a regular tidyverse user now, I benefit a lot from the transition from base R to higher level R language in sophisticated packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network visualization (part3)</title>
      <link>/post/network_analysis_part3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/network_analysis_part3/</guid>
      <description>In the previous two posts (part1, part2), we discussed about IGRAPH object and how to manipulate, measure and cluster it. In this part3 of network analysis series, I will focus on the network work visualization.
Network visualization are supported by two aspects — the aestheic part of network elements (aka, vertices and edges) and layout of network. There are multiple packages available for these aspects. I will focus on the basic igraph plot (more like base R plot) and the application of ggraph (comparable to ggplot2)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network analysis part2</title>
      <link>/post/network_analysis_part2-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/network_analysis_part2-2/</guid>
      <description>In last post, we cover the basic components of IGRAPH objects and how to manipulate IGRAPH. You may notice that most of those manipulation do not really require a IGRAPH object to play with. However, in this post, you will realize the advantage of using IGRAPH in network analysis and how operation on IGRAPH object is much easier than using data.frame when doing network analysis.
In this session, we are going to use a new undirected graph (gr) generated by sample_gnp().</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hi I&#39;m Sckinta</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am Chun (Sckinta) and I am currently a bioinformatics scientist at the Children’s Hospital of Philadelphia. Originally from China, I moved to the U.S. in 2011 and completed my PhD in Biology at the University of Virginia in 2017. Starting as a Perl programmer, I picked up R and Python on my own by taking online courses and local meetup workshops. I enjoy learning new programming skills and believe learning is a life-time mission and practice makes perfect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Analysis in R (part1)</title>
      <link>/post/network_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/network_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Network analysis is to study the complexity of the inter-relationships between actors of all sorts and provides an architectural view of individual actor connections. It has been applied to many fields, like social network and gene network, and useful for any systematic studies on individual relationship. wiki
This post plus following two posts (part2, part3) aim to introduce the termilogy that are frequently used in network and public available R tools that are useful for network analysis and visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>